Guide to the Antonio Ochoa Carrillo Papers and Benito Juárez Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Papers and Correspondence, 1852-1871; 0.42; (1 box) + 1 broadside folder
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: El Paso del Norte, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1866 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    Juárez expresses his belief that French will abandon Mexico within five months. He includes clippings (non-extant) related to the response by United States Secretary of State William Henry Seward to news that Austrian soldiers might replace the French in Mexico by threatening to sever diplomatic relations with Austria and the possibility of war. Juárez also includes clippings (non-extant) related to General Jesús González Ortega.
  - Ochoa Carrillo, Antonio. Autograph draft letter: to Benito Juárez, 1866 June 19, 29 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Juárez reports that positive news from Sinaloa and Sonora, and expects the Mexican Empire to yield soon. He does mention difficulties connected to the port at Altata in Sinaloa.
    In his draft reply, Ochoa suggests that the government authorize merchants to run the blockade without a public declaration.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: Chihuahua, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1866 July 3 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    Juárez reports that Austria capitulated to the demands of the United States government and recalled troops en route to Mexico.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: Chihuahua, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1866 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Juárez mentions the continued difficulties at the port at Altata in Sinaloa. He also reports the Republican victories in Tamaulipas and Nuevo León over Mexican Empire troops commanded by General Tomás Mejía.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: Chihuahua, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1866 July 24 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    Juárez relays reports from the United States and throughout Mexico that French troops have nearly left the country, and that French General François Achille Bazaine has explicit orders not to provide military or financial assistance to Maximilian.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: Chihuahua, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1866 July 31 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    Juárez reports his authorization to Sinaloa Governor Domingo Rubí to provide permission for shipping goods from the port at Altata through the agency of Juan Sepúlveda. He also summarizes Republican victories in Tamaulipas, near Camargo, as well as the capture of Matamoros.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: Chihuahua, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1866 August 21 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    Juárez reports the retreat of French troops to San Luis Potosí before troops under the command of General Mariano Antonio Guadalupe Escobedo de la Peña, as well as the Republican occupation of Monterrey in Nuevo León, and Saltillo in Coahuila.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: Chihuahua, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1866 August 28 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    Juárez reports the continued retreat of French troops, and that a coalition of "traitors" and French troops remains loyal to Maximilian in Durango.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: Chihuahua, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1866 September 25 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    Juárez reports his expectation that the remaining French troops will leave Guaymas in Sonora, and Mazatlán in Sinaloa. He adds that Ochoa should not worry about the arrival in Sinaloa of its former governor, General Don Plácido de la Vega Daza y Colon de Portugal, because Juárez ordered General Ramón Corona to take charge of all the military in the region.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: Chihuahua, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1866 October 9 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    Juárez briefly reports that imminent departure of French troops from Sinaloa and Durango.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: Chihuahua, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1866 October 16 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    Juárez asks for news from Sinaloa, and reports that troops en route to Durango under the command of General Silvestre Aranda.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: Chihuahua, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1866 November 6 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    Juárez reports delays related to troops en route to Chihuahua commanded by General Don Plácido de la Vega Daza y Colon de Portugal and the disingenuous excuses Vega provided for the delay. He also reports that Maximilian remains in Mexico, although he expects him to leave the country.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: Chihuahua, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1866 November 13 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    Juárez expresses his sorrow upon learning of the death of Juan Sepúlveda, and plans for his replacement. He also mentions that General Don Plácido de la Vega Daza y Colon de Portugal appears loyal to the Republic and en route to Chihuahua.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: Chihuahua, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo., 1866 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    Juárez reports that the Republic will provide the Juan Sepúlveda a payment of 10,000 pesos.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: Chihuahua, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1866 November 27 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    Juárez briefly requests confirmation that the French left Mazatlán in Sinaloa. He also reports that French troops have left Durango prior to the arrival of Colonel Abel Pereyra.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: Chihuahua, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1866 December 4 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    Juárez expresses his gratitude to Ochoa for confirmation that the French left Mazatlán in Sinaloa, and his attention to the estate of Juan Sepúlveda. He reports that he will leave for Durango on December 10, 1866.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: Durango, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1867 January 8 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    Juárez acknowledges the petition on behalf of the estate of Juan Sepúlveda. He reports his arrival in Durango on December 26, 1866, and that he will soon travel to Zacatecas, He also reports Republican control of San Luis Potosí and Jalisco, while remnants of the Empire retain control of Guanajuato and Querétaro.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: San Luis Potosí, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1867 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    Juárez briefly discusses the recommendation by Ochoa of Ibarra. He also reports that the Republican government will soon return to Mexico City, and that troops under the command of General José de la Cruz Porfirio Díaz Mori will soon break the a siege of Querétaro.
  - Juárez, Benito. Secretarial letter, signed: Mexico City, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1867 December 28 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    Juárez briefly reports his presidential inauguration the previous day.
  - Corona, Ramón. Secretarial letter, signed: Mazatlán, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1868 May 21 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    Corona reports rumors that soldiers defeated in battle at Villa de Union, Chihuahua, are organizing in the mountains of Morelos, and that he sent General Francisco Tolentino to pursue them.
  - Juárez, Benito. Autograph letter, signed: Mexico City, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1870 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    Juárez briefly sends his regards to Ochoa with the bearer of the letter, Don Juan Maria Palomier.
  - Corona, Ramón. Autograph letter, signed: Durango, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1870 December 30 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    Corona expresses his thoughts on the presidential elections in June 1871, and declares his support for Benito Juárez rather than General José de la Cruz Porfirio Díaz Mori or Sebastián Lerdo de Tejada y Corral. He also asks Ochoa which candidate he supports in the election.
  - Corona, Ramón. Autograph letter, signed: Guadalajara, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1871 April 2 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    Corona expresses his pleasure that Ochoa also supports Juárez for president. He also reports on the peaceful transfer of the governorship from Antonio Gómez Cuervo to Jesús Leandro Camarena.
  - Corona, Ramón. Autograph letter, signed: Guadalajara, to Antonio Ochoa Carrillo, 1871 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    Corona tanks Ochoa for subscribing to José María Vigil and Juan B. Hijar y Haro, Ensayo histórico del Ejército de Occidente (México: Ignacio Cumplido, 1871). He also reports the turbulent nature of politics in Guadalajara.